<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Wanjing Chen</title><link href="https://cwjwanjing.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://cwjwanjing.github.io/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://cwjwanjing.github.io/</id><updated>2021-02-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Usability Study of iPhone X Side Button</title><link href="https://cwjwanjing.github.io/blog/iPhoneXSideButton" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-02-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-02-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Wanjing Chen</name></author><id>tag:cwjwanjing.github.io,2021-02-26:/blog/iPhoneXSideButton</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/iPhoneX_SideButton/summaryimage.png" alt="" class="headerimg"/&gt;I performed a study regarding the usability of the iPhone X Side Button in 2020 as a course project for the course &lt;em&gt;Human Factor: Working with Users&lt;/em&gt;. Back then, social distancing just introduced due to COVID-19, I did the study a bit differently.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this study is to evaluate the functioning of the iPhone X's side button. The problem I found is that the behaviour of long-pressing the side button is unexpected on the iPhone X, triggering the voice assistant, Siri &lt;em&gt;(Apple, 2020)&lt;/em&gt;, instead of shutting down the phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Android smartphones and previous iPhones before the iPhone X, long-pressing the side button will allow users to shut down the phone. The iPhone X subverts this expected behaviour by instead launching Siri. Users will be confused when encountering this behaviour for the first time. &lt;em&gt;(Reddit, 2018)&lt;/em&gt; The number of times people searching 'shut down iPhone' increased a lot after the iPhone X released. &lt;em&gt;(Wikipedia, 2020)&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;(Google trends, 2020)&lt;/em&gt; Shutting down the iPhone X is more complicated now, requiring the user to simultaneously hold one of the volume buttons and the power button. Then the screen will display a "slide to power off" bar that the user can use to power off the device. &lt;em&gt;(Apple support, 2020)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to find out the possible reasons for Apple to change the side button's functionality and ways to make the button more usable. I, therefore, focused on testing users' attitudes toward the change and their potential suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="image"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/iPhoneX_SideButton/side_button.png" alt=""&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The Side Button&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="image"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/iPhoneX_SideButton/trriger_siri.png" alt=""&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Triggers Siri&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="image"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/iPhoneX_SideButton/power_off.png" alt=""&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Power off&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="image"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/iPhoneX_SideButton/google_trend.png" alt=""&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Google Trend&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The motivation for studying this problem comes from many aspects. Below I consider aspects of the ABCS &lt;em&gt;(Ritter/Baxter/Churchill, 2014)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Behavioural factor&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: perceived affordance &lt;em&gt;(Norman, D. A., 1990)&lt;/em&gt; is subverted since the button's behaviour changed while the layout remains the same.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cognitive factor&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: the users' &lt;em&gt;Mental Models of system operation&lt;/em&gt; have to change. Since iPhone users are already familiar with previous iPhones, they'd assume long-pressing the side button will lead to shutting down the phone based on their previous experiences. Changing a mental model can be challenging; while it is possible, it is a lot of work. &lt;em&gt;(Chi, 2008)&lt;/em&gt; Since users of previous iPhones struggle to power off the phone, so would Android phone users and others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at 7 Questions Driving User-Centred Systems &lt;em&gt;(Ritter/Baxter/Churchill, 2014)&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Functionality&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: the purpose of the change is to compensate for removing the home button. The side button is now used for the features of Siri and Apple Pay. &lt;em&gt;(Woollaston, 2018)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Usability&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Based on personal experience, when I first found out the side button of iPhone X does not have the power-off function, it was 15 minutes before the exam to start, I was already stressed, this made it worse. Therefore, as a veteran iPhone user, according to the definition of usability &lt;em&gt;(ISO standard 9241)&lt;/em&gt;, I would say it is not very usable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Learnability&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: it is easy to learn the new way to shut down iPhone X, as users just need to look up the Apple support documentation and practice using it. However, it is inconsistent with the way other iPhones work. &lt;em&gt;(Kendra S./Theo J.D., 2017)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Efficiency&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: the efficiency of the new way to power off the phone decreases since users need to long-press both a volume button and the side button until the power off slider appears, not as before, we just need to long-press the side button.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reliability&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: once users get used to the new power-off method, the function of the side button will remain consistent through the lifetime of the phone, so it is reliable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The design change is acceptable in some aspects; however, in most of the points mentioned above, the design has some issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Participant&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participants were selected from people who have never used an iPhone X before, such as people who use Android phones only or people who use previous versions of iPhones only. People who have already used iPhone X before or know the iPhone X very well were not recruited. Since they were already familiar with it, they might have forgotten how they found the design change at first. I did not choose any participants under 18 or any other vulnerable people in my study. I recruited three people in total. Recruitment were done through friends and students who also took &lt;em&gt;The Human Factor&lt;/em&gt; at the University of Edinburgh, participating in their studies in return as an incentive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Method&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study was completed through video calls using WeChat to imitate the paper prototyping method and observe social distancing. Both participants and I made sure we were under stable internet connections and without distractions. Before the study began, I sent digital consent forms to participants, notifying them what data will be taken from them. I did not collect participants' personal or confidential data. After they signed the consent form, information sheets were given to participants for consistent information delivery among all participants, including the purpose of this study, what the process will be, and what task they will be doing. In the meantime, I answered any questions they had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When all information was delivered, they were asked to turn off their phones during the study, and I presented them with the iPhone X through the video call. They said their actions out loud. I acted as both facilitator, speaking with participants, explaining what is going on, and taking notes; and the computer, showing participants the device state reacting to participants' actions. Their task was shutting down the iPhone X. During the study, they were allowed to use the internet to search for information to shut down the iPhone X. The number and the kinds of steps they take to complete the task, such as opening system preferences or searching 'iPhone X shut down' in a search engine were recorded. The greater the number of steps or the greater the variety of steps taken, the less usable the side button is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the call, an electronic survey powered by &lt;em&gt;Typeform&lt;/em&gt; was immediately delivered to each participant regarding whether they completed the task or not, and their satisfaction and experience with the design change. Questions like 'how useful the change of design is', ranging from 'Very useful' to 'Not useful at all', and 'how did you find the new way of powering off' were featured in the questionnaire. The possible reasons for the design change and suggestions for possible enhancements in the design were also asked in the survey. The questionnaire looked like the figure below. All the data were kept digitally and encrypted, no Google products were used. Qualitative data was based on participants' answers in the survey, and quantitative data was based on the steps and categories recorded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="image"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/iPhoneX_SideButton/questionnaire.png" alt=""&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The Questionnaire&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Analysis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The analysis included descriptive statistics such as the average number and categories of steps participants take to complete the task, the modal number of the choice people make regarding the question 'how useful the change of design is' were computed. The higher the average number of steps participants take, the more complex it is to use the side button, the less usable for the side button to perform powering off. The modal number of the choice made can show what attitudes participants hold. I used pie charts to analyse participants' responses. I compared and grouped suggestions for possible enhancements and the participants' reasons for the change in design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were three participants recruited through my friends. They were all aged 21 to 23 years old and female. They are all university students with good experience with electronic devices such as smartphones and computers but hadn't used the iPhone X before and weren't aware of the change in functionality of the side button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recorded the number of steps participants took to complete the task and how many of them completed the task. I also recorded how useful they think the change of design is and how easy they find powering off the phone using the new design. In the end, I asked what they think of the possible reasons for Apple to change this design and what their suggestions are for improving the usability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="image"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/iPhoneX_SideButton/figure1.png" alt=""&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As shown in Figure 1, all of them completed the task of powering off the iPhone X successfully. Two participants, i.e. 66.7% participants, as shown in Figure 2, found that the change of design is not useful at all for powering off, and one remains neutral. Each of them holds different views towards the new way of powering off, one thinks it's easy to use, one thinks it's hard to use, and one thinks it's very hard to use. The below table shows participants' opinions towards the potential reason for changing the design and their suggestions for improvement:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="image"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/iPhoneX_SideButton/participants-suggests.png" alt=""&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="image"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/iPhoneX_SideButton/figure2.png" alt=""&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the participants assumed it's because of the removal of the home button, and one seemed unsure. Still, she cannot understand why Siri is important enough to replace the side button's functionality for powering off. Most participants mentioned adding another button, but one of them stated that it would then lose the meaning of reducing the home button. They also mentioned different types of pressing the side buttons to trigger either powering off or SIRI, such as "triple click" or "long press". An interesting suggestion would be using time regulation to differ the SIRI and power off functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Discussion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By assessing the usability of this new design in terms of efficiency and subjective satisfaction, the results showed me low usability. By considering the efficiency by counting how many steps on average have been taken, the efficiency is low. The expected steps for people using a phone for the first time are 2 steps, i.e. long-press the side button and then slide the power-off sign because people are used to standard phones. Since the average is 4.67 steps, comparing with the expected steps, it's more than twice of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The small number of participants reduced the generalizability of the conclusions drawn from these results since the participants all don't regularly use Siri, so their attitudes towards the design change could be biased. On top of this, the participants were all from a very narrow demographic, and so the study can't comment on how other demographics would react to the change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found during the experiments that telling people to power off the phone primed them to think that it wouldn't be as simple as they would expect. This was evidenced by two participants not attempting to long-press the side button as their first action. I would change this in a future study by telling participants that it was a usability study of the iPhone X, as opposed to specifically mentioning that it is about the change in side button functionality. I would also add other steps before switching off the phone to put participants at ease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the effect of the pandemic, the measure of time taken by the participants to complete the task cannot be achieved. Otherwise, the efficiency could be measured in this way. Also, it was difficult for participants to see what was on the screen, due to some unstable connections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Proposed Solution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on my data, most people find it inconvenient to power off the new way instead of the old way. According to their proposed possible suggestions, I considered "long press" remains for powering off, and "three clicks" for SIRI since most people could trigger Siri by saying "Hey Siri". ("double clicks" is reserved for Apple pay) This is motivated by my data since all three participants mentioned changing the behaviour of the button back to the old "long-press to power off" way. On top of this, the participants believed that the change was due to the removal of the home button, and this change would not go against that motivation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple (2020), Siri does more than ever. Even before you ask. Available at &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/uk/siri/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;reddit (2018) [help] Can't turn off phone because of Siri. Available at &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/jailbreak/comments/7uj0n9/help_cant_turn_off_phone_because_of_siri/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wikipedia (2020), iPhone X. Available at &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IPhone_X"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google trends (2020) Available at &lt;a href="https://trends.google.com/trends/explore?date=2016-01-01\%202020-02-23\&amp;amp;q=shut\%20down\%20iphone"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple support (2020), Restart your iPhone. Available at &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-gb/HT201559"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ritter/Baxter/Churchill (2014), Foundations for Designing User-Centred Systems, Springer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Norman, D. A. (1990), The Design of Everyday Things. New York: Doubleday&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michelene T. H. Chi (2008), International Handbook of Research on Conceptual Change, Chap.3 Three Types of Conceptual Change: Belief Revision, Mental Model Transformation, and Categorical Shift, P69-70&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Victoria Woollaston (2018) iPhone X review: Apple's expensive iPhone X is still a thing of beauty. Available at &lt;a href="https://www.alphr.com/apple/1007009/apple-iphone-x-review"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ISO standard 9241&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kendra S./Theo J.D. (2017), Libri: The International Journal of Libraries and Information Studies, P106&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Appendix&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A Participant Information Sheet&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object type="application/pdf"
    data="/files/cwj_pis_informatics.pdf"
    width="500"
    height="450"&gt;
&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;B Participant Consent Form&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object type="application/pdf"
    data="/files/PCF.pdf"
    width="500"
    height="450"&gt;
&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="uxr"></category></entry><entry><title>An international student in Edinburgh - Part 2</title><link href="https://cwjwanjing.github.io/blog/Riego-street" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-06-16T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-06-16T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Wanjing Chen</name></author><id>tag:cwjwanjing.github.io,2020-06-16:/blog/Riego-street</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/riego/riegostreet.jpg" alt="" class="headerimg"/&gt; I didn’t get my first choice of accommodation at the University of Edinburgh, I ended up in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Riego Street&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, but I had a good experience.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I studied A levels, a British qualification, in order to study abroad. After my A levels, I decided to go to the University of Edinburgh. This is a story about how I got my accommodation in Year 1, and how it turned out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My A level exam board was CIE, so my grades only came out in August. This, along with some personal issues, meant that I applied for university accommodation quite late.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Renting accommodation privately was not an option since I was not in the UK and could not view flats in person. That meant that university accommodation was my safest bet. Each person was allowed to have five accommodation choices. All of my choices were ensuite because it's a little inconvenient to share one bathroom with four or more people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, when the accommodation assignments came out, I didn't get any of my potential choices. I was assigned to a place called &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Riego Street&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; instead. It was not ensuite. I heard that people got assigned here because they applied late for the accommodation. All of the other choices were already taken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In high school, I lived in a room of four, and we shared a bathroom. That's usually the case for universities in China. So it was alright for me to share a bathroom with other people, and the idea of having my own room already pleased me. I couldn't wait to decorate it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Riego Street&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Riego Street complex forms a U shape; my building was in the middle. When I arrived at the accommodation I saw a big yellow sign which had the University of Edinburgh's logo on it, and 'Riego Street' in big letters. My accommodation is here!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/riego/riegostreet.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I stood at the entrance, I saw many volunteers (most of them were students from higher years), and a red door leading to the reception. A volunteer took me through and gave me an information pack. All the information I needed to know about the accommodation was in there. Then I followed the volunteer to my flat door. After handing me the key, he left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/riego/riegobuilding.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was an A4 paper on the door. It was printed with the Scotland flag and the name of each person who lives in this apartment. My roommates were all nice, they invited me to hang out with them a lot. One of them was from Poland, one of them was Scottish, and one of them was from Malaysia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/riego/flatdoorflag.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw a 10-meter-ish hallway when I opened the flat door. The first room on the left side was the kitchen. It was reasonably spacious. There were four hobs, one sink, one fridge, one dining table, several dining chairs, two big sofas and a tea table—also a toaster, a microwave oven, an oven and some cookware left by previous people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, we had a washing machine. Washing machines were usually shared by the entire building in other accommodation and cost money. A wash cycle (no drying) would normally be around £3. I only need to share with four people, and we didn't need to pay to use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only problems were that there were only four hobs and one refrigerator. My roommates and I all cooked very often. Two people cooking at once got crowded, not to mention three or four people. We could not buy too much food. Otherwise, the fridge got filled up too easily. Thankfully, all of us were considerate. We tried to stagger meal times and to buy the amount of food we would eat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(The picture below is the view from the kitchen window. I took it because I thought my roommates' decoration was cute.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/riego/kitchenwindowoutside.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next room on the left-hand side was the biggest bathroom in the flat. It had a toilet, a sink and a shower. There was another bathroom in the flat which had the same facilities but was smaller. One of the best bits about our flat was that although we had five people, we had two bathrooms which both had a shower. Unlike other four-person flats, which normally have one bathroom with a shower and maybe one extra bathroom without a shower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/riego/riegoflatlayout.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two rooms after the bathroom were bedrooms. The end of the hallway was the smaller bathroom mentioned earlier and a storage room. On the right-hand side of the hallway, there were the remaining three rooms. The rooms were labelled 'A B C D E' respectively. I lived in A.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/riego/riegobedroomlayout.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would say my room was spacious. You could see a big cork notice board on the wall, and below that, there was a heater. On the right-hand side of the room, there was an OK-sized desk with a shelf above it. Next to the desk was a sink. I didn't expect a sink in my room, but it was very convenient. Even when I have morning classes, I didn't need to compete with my roommates for the toilets. The only nuisance was that it was placed opposite the bed. Sometimes when I woke up to pee during the night, my reflection in the mirror shocked me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A single bed was in the left corner, and you could see it when you enter the room, facing the wardrobe. There was a bedside table near the bed. The wardrobe was big enough for me. The single bed was a bit small but matched the size of my quilt cover. The window was placed between the bed and the sink. Sometimes I would use it to people-watch after class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things that surprised me about accommodation in the UK, was their sound insulation. At first, I thought it was only Riego Street which did not have good sound insulation. But I later found out that almost all accommodation (apart from some new builds) had the same problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you speak in the hallway, you need to be prepared for your conversations to be heard by other people. The door seemed to be mostly decorative. However, the sound insulation between each room was alright.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="image"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/riego/riegosurroundingsmap.png" alt=""&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;This graph was made using Google My map&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The location of Riego Street was perfect. The nearest supermarket was 2 minutes walk away. And there was a good range of supermarkets; Tesco Express, Co-op Food, Sainsbury's Local. I went to Sainsbury's Local and Co-op Food most often, because Sainsbury's Local is on my way to school; Co-op Food was the nearest supermarket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A very special thing for me was that there was a Chinese supermarket very close, “Oriental Supermarket”. It was really convenient since I cook Chinese dishes a lot. If I was cooking and forgot an ingredient, it only took me 3 minutes to get it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except for supermarkets, when I wanted to buy toiletries, there was also a Boots and a Superdrug nearby. Even the bank was very close. My bank is RBS, and there was an RBS next door. I like drawing, and there was an art shop in the neighbourhood. Sometimes when I was free, I would go around the shop. Just looking at those painting tools would make me feel happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I wanted to see a movie, I had two choices of cinemas. One was ODEON, and the other was Filmhouse. They were both within 5 minutes walking distance. I was surprised for my first time in Filmhouse because they don't reserve seats, it was first come first serve. I thought all European cinemas were like this until I went to ODEON. Filmhouse was unusual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I wanted to go to a concert, the Usher Hall was a good choice. There was a performance almost every night. It was a pity that I didn't find out about it until my second year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main shopping street, Princes Street was just over 10 minutes walk. It took a similar time to get to Edinburgh Castle. I often took a walk with friends there after dinner. Since the castle is on the hill, when you look down at the city during sunset, you can feel the beauty of the city even more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Occasionally, when I didn't want to cook, there were also many restaurants for me to choose. There are Japanese cuisine, Chinese cuisine, China Red (Chinese buffet), grilled fish store, Korean cuisine, Nando's (fried chicken) and lots more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I study computer science, so my classes were all on the main campus. It took me 15 minutes walk to the campus. So I didn't need to worry about being late for lectures even if I woke up late.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a shame that I didn't take many photos of the accommodation. I can only recall the pictures in my mind. Overall, I think Riego Street was good accommodation, it was definitely good value for money. All bills were included in the price of 125 pounds a week. Even though I didn't get my first choice of accommodation, I was pleased being assigned there.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="stories"></category></entry><entry><title>我在英国爱丁堡大学留学的故事（二）</title><link href="https://cwjwanjing.github.io/Riego-street-Chinese.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-06-16T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-06-16T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>陈皖静</name></author><id>tag:cwjwanjing.github.io,2020-06-16:/Riego-street-Chinese.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/riego/riegostreet.jpg" alt="" class="headerimg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;因为很早就有出国的打算，所以我高中学的是A level课程，相当于英国的“高考”。高三考完出成绩之后，我决定了去爱丁堡大学读书。这篇文章讲述的是我是如何住进了我大一的宿舍和我的居住体验。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我的A level是由 CIE 的考试局负责的，八月份才出成绩。再加上个人原因，所以我申请宿舍申请得比较晚。当时也没想过要在外面自己租房子，因为毕竟我人不在英国没法实地看房子。申请学校宿舍是我最好的选择。每个学生可以选五个宿舍意向。我选的都是独立卫浴的，因为和别人共用一个卫生间有时候会不太方便。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;然而宿舍分配结果出来的时候我选的宿舍一个都没有分到。而是被分到了一个叫做 &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Riego Street&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; 的宿舍。不是独立卫浴的。据说被分到这个宿舍的人大多数都是因为申请得太迟了，选的宿舍都没有位置了。我高中是在国内高中国际部上的，宿舍是四个人一间，然后共用一个卫生间，跟国内大多数大学差不多。所以相比于跟别人共用一个房间，能有一个自己的房间我也已经感到满足。我都迫不及待去装饰我的房间啦！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Riego Street&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Riego Street 单元楼的分布是呈U型，我的单元楼在角落的地方。刚到宿舍楼底下就看到了一块有着爱丁堡大学logo的黄色的标牌，上面写着几个大字“Riego Street”。就是这儿了，我的宿舍！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/riego/riegostreet.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;入口处显而易见地能看到在门口迎接的志愿者们（大多是学长学姐），和一扇红色的门——新生接待处入口。一名志愿者带我进了那扇红色的门，然后给了我一个文件袋，里面有各种我需要知道的住宿内容，注意事项等等。接着我便跟着他抵达了我的公寓门口，他把钥匙递交给我之后便离开了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/riego/riegobuilding.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;公寓的门上贴着印有苏格兰旗子的A4纸，上面写了每个住在这个宿舍的人的名字。我的室友都很友好，经常邀请我一起跟他们参加活动。他们有的来自波兰，有的是苏格兰当地人，有的来自马来西亚。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/riego/flatdoorflag.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;一进宿舍便看到了一条大约十米的走廊，左手边第一间便是厨房。厨房还算宽敞，有四个灶台，一个水槽，一个冰箱，一个吃饭的圆桌，几把餐椅，还有两个大沙发和一个“茶几”。有烤面包机，微波炉，烤箱，还有一些别人留下来的锅具可以用。最重要的是我们有洗衣机。大多数宿舍洗衣机都是一栋楼的人共用的，而且要额外收费，每用一次洗衣机（不加烘干）是3磅左右（人名币25块左右）。我们只是五个人共用而且不用交钱。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;不过厨房美中不足的是只有四个灶台和一个冰箱，我和我的室友都是做饭比较勤的，有时候两个人一起煮灶台会有点拥挤，更别说三个四个人了；冰箱东西不能买多也不能屯货不然会放不下。好在我们每个人都很善解人意，都会尽量错开做饭时间，也会吃多少买多少。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;（下面这张照片是从厨房看向外面的样子，我觉得室友用花装饰过的窗台很温馨于是拍了下来： ）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/riego/kitchenwindowoutside.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;走廊左手边再过去便是公寓里最大的卫生间，有座便器、洗手池和淋浴间。公寓里有另一个洗手间，跟这个洗手间有一样的设施，不过空间小一些。我们宿舍的优点是虽然我们是五个人，但是有两个同时拥有淋浴间的宿舍。别的四人间的宿舍他们只有一个这样的卫生间，最多还有一个只有座便器和洗手池的卫生间。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/riego/riegoflatlayout.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;卫生间再过去便是两个卧室，走廊的尽头是上面说到的小的卫生间和一个储物室，走廊的右手边便是剩下的三个卧室。房间从左到右依次标为 A B C D E，我住在 A。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/riego/riegobedroomlayout.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我的房间还算宽敞，一进门就能看到右边墙上有一个大告示板（可以写东西），下面有一个电热器。右手边还有一张够大的书桌，书桌上方有一个书架。书桌的左边是洗漱台。房间里还有一个洗漱台是我没有想到的，不过有它真的很方便，就算有早课也不用跟室友抢着去卫生间洗漱。唯一弊端就是它正对着床，我半夜去上厕所的时候偶尔会被镜子里的自己吓到。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;进门左上方角落里有一张单人床，正对着衣柜，床的旁边是一个床头柜。衣橱于我而言足够大。单人床对我来说稍微小了一点点，不过刚好和我的被子大小配套。在床和洗漱台之间有一扇窗。后来的我常常喜欢在傍晚观察路上的行人。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;英国的宿舍让我感到惊讶的地方是它的隔音，一开始我以为只是我们 Riego Street 隔音不太好，后来发现如果不是新建的楼房的话，隔音都不是太好。如果你在走廊上说话，那就要做好对话清晰地被别人听见的准备，就好像房门是摆设似的。不过我们宿舍房间与房间之间的隔音还可以。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="image"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/riego/riegosurroundingsmap.png" alt=""&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;这张图是用Google My map来制作的&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Riego Street 的地理位置真的很好。下楼两分钟就可以到最近的超市，而且超市的选择特别多。有 Tesco Express，有 Co-op Food，有 Sainsbury's Local。我经常去 Sainsbury's Local 和 Co-op Food，因为 Sainsbury's Local 在我上下学的路上， Co-op Food 下楼两分钟就到了。还有一点对我来说特别重要的是有一家很近的中超 “Oriental Supermarket”，对于经常做中国菜的我来说方便到不行。有时候临时想做一样东西就下个楼，要不了3分钟就到超市了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;除了超市以外，有时候我想集中地买生活用品，附近也有一家 Boots 和一家 Superdrug。就连银行也特别近，我办的刚好是 RBS 的银行卡，Riego 附近就有一家 RBS 银行。我喜欢画画，刚好旁边有一家卖画具的店，有时候闲着没事做我也会进去溜达一圈。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;要说娱乐的话，想看电影了有两家电影院可以选，一家 ODEON ，一家 Filmhouse，也就走路五分钟的事。我第一次去 Filmhouse 的时候有点吃惊，因为他们的电影票是不标座位号的，先到先得。我以为欧洲电影院都是这样，直到我去了 ODEON，才发现那只是特例。想听音乐会的话，可以去 Usher Hall ，几乎每晚都有表演。可惜大一我没有利用这个地理优势，大二才开始跑到这边来看演出。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;爱丁堡主要的购物街——王子街12分钟路程左右就到了，吃什么买什么都方便。爱丁堡城堡也是差不多路程，有时候和朋友就这么吃完晚饭走路散步到城堡门口。因为城堡在山上，傍晚时分俯瞰整个城市，你能更加感受到这座城市的魅力。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;有时候我不想做饭，附近也有好多餐馆，有好几家日料，中餐，还有 China Red（自助中餐），烤鱼店，韩料，Nando's（炸鸡店）啦，简直不能再方便了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;最重要一点就是上学，因为我学计算机的，课全都是在主校区上的，Riego Street 离爱丁堡大学主校区15分钟路程，每天早上不用起很早也不用担心迟到。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;可惜的是我没有拍多少宿舍的照片，只能凭脑海中的画面来回忆。总而言之呢，我觉得 Riego Street 是一个很好的宿舍，性价比特别高，水电啊或者其他的费用都包括在125磅一周的价格里。虽然我没有选中自己一开始想要的宿舍，但是被分到这里我觉得挺满意的。&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="stories"></category></entry><entry><title>An international student in Edinburgh - Part 1</title><link href="https://cwjwanjing.github.io/blog/Edinburgh" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-06-04T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-06-04T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Wanjing Chen</name></author><id>tag:cwjwanjing.github.io,2020-06-04:/blog/Edinburgh</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/macdonald/airport.jpg" alt="" class="headerimg"/&gt; This is the story of my first evening in Edinburgh. Something unexpected happened...&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Preface&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the midst of a global pandemic, and without realising it, 2020 has entered June. Initially, my graduation ceremony would have been held in 20 days. However, due to the coronavirus, it’s still up in the air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started to think back on my degree and even what I might have done differently given the chance. I’ve learned many things and experienced many things. Here I want to share some of the most memorable examples. This is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;An international student in Edinburgh - Part 1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;One night in McDonald's&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the 8th of September, 2016, I flew to the UK. It was 9ish in the evening when I arrived at Edinburgh airport. Just after I stepped outside the plane, I felt a chill in the air. Edinburgh evenings in September are cold. The moment when the customs officer stamped my passport, I knew my life of studying abroad had begun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The image of me arriving the airport" src="/images/macdonald/airport.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since my university accommodation was available for checking in only from the 10th of September, and I was planning to familiarise myself with Edinburgh's environment earlier than that, I booked a hotel before my departure. Carrying my luggage; a big suitcase, a small suitcase and a backpack, I got in the taxi. I figured taking a taxi would be the safest choice for me, given that I knew nothing about Edinburgh’s buses and it was already dark. I didn't want to get lost. During the ride, the driver was friendly, introducing the tourist spots as we passed by them, such as this is the castle, this is Prince’s Street (the place for shopping) etc. When we reached the end of our conversation, I arrived at the hotel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was late and I was exhausted from my flight, so I was hoping to check in quickly. However, just as I was imagining a soft, warm bed, the reception staff told me that he couldn’t find my booking! How could this be possible?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took out my phone and showed him my booking confirmation letter, he had a glance at it and then rechecked the list, even turning the computer screen for me to see. Surprisingly, the booking lists on that night genuinely didn't have my name on it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After he read the confirmation letter thoroughly, we realised what the problem was. It's because I took the flight at 9:30 PM Chinese time on the 8th of September. My hotel booking was for the 9th of September. However, I’d forgotten to take into account time going backwards as I flew west, and so I had landed in Edinburgh still on the 8th of September! No wonder my name was not on the booking list…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The image of hotel staff telling me my name was not on the booking list" src="/images/macdonald/hotel.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first time in the UK (alone!) and this unexpected thing happened; I was stunned into silence for a while. The first thing came to my mind was asking them if they have any rooms available tonight. They said no. Then I thought maybe I could ask them if I could stay in the lobby for tonight and check in tomorrow? Again they said no, probably because other customers might find a strange girl sleeping in the lobby off-putting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later on, it might be due to my tiredness or my unfamiliarity with the surroundings, not to mention I wasn’t very experienced, I called a taxi without thinking further. I asked the driver to take me to the nearby hotels and ask each one whether they have rooms available tonight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One by one the hotels said no. I was wondering why I was so unlucky, why every hotel we visited did not have a room available? But I thought, Edinburgh is surely busy in the tourist season, and the driver is so kind, asking the hotels for me every time. When I look back on it right now, the hotels we visited looked all very fancy, and the travelling times between each hotel were at least 10 minutes, I guess he was just racking up a nice fare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the number in the taximeter was increasing past 40 pounds and the time displayed on the phone was already twelve o'clock, I thought that I couldn't keep doing this any longer. I decided to stay at a 24-hour McDonald's. On the way there, I rechecked the booking confirmation letter, surprisingly, I realised it was actually a youth hostel. (There are very few youth hostels in China, so I assumed it was a hotel.) I wasn’t comfortable with the idea of living with strangers in a room, so I cancelled the booking, and booked another hotel for the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The image of me staying at McDonald's" src="/images/macdonald/mcdonald.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From then, my 15-hour stay at McDonald's started. I felt really sleepy, but I forced myself to stay awake in case my luggage was stolen. I tried to comfort myself by thinking "thankfully I'm not staying on the street, and I still have food".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the early morning, around three or four o'clock, I met four Chinese people in the McDonald's. They had hotel problems too and were in the same boat as me. I felt less lonely and a little comforted. The next day I successfully checked in, and afterwards successfully moved in my student accommodation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My parents back then were not able to get their visas in time, and I considered myself independent enough, so I decided to come to Edinburgh alone for my first time in the UK. Experiencing this kind of thing at the beginning of my study abroad seems funny to me when I think about it now. I was quite inexperienced, but I had a positive attitude at least. I encouraged myself that I've used up all the bad luck, and the rest will all be good luck. That was my first impression of Edinburgh, which I think I'll never forget.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="first"></category><category term="stories"></category></entry><entry><title>我在英国爱丁堡大学留学的故事（一）</title><link href="https://cwjwanjing.github.io/Edinburgh-Chinese.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-06-03T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-06-03T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>陈皖静</name></author><id>tag:cwjwanjing.github.io,2020-06-03:/Edinburgh-Chinese.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/macdonald/airport.jpg" alt="" class="headerimg"/&gt; 这是我来到爱丁堡的第一个晚上发生的故事，没想到会发生这样的事情...&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;前言&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;不知不觉，在全球疫情笼罩之下，2020年已经进入六月。再过20多天，理论上应该是举行我毕业典礼的日子。但是很可惜，因为疫情的原因没法如期举行了,延期到具体什么时候还是改成网上毕业典礼暂时还是个问号。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;本科生涯接近尾声，我不禁开始思考，四年海外留学我到底经历并收获了什么，又有哪些如果时光倒流我会特别想去做的事情。我将以“我在英国爱丁堡大学留学的故事”系列来回顾大学四年所发生的各种难忘的事情。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;麦当劳留宿记&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2016年9月8号我坐上了远赴英国的航班，飞机抵达爱丁堡的时候是晚上九点左右，刚下飞机我就感受到了阵阵寒意，九月的爱丁堡的夜晚是寒冷的。海关的工作人员在给我敲上入境盖章的那一刹那，我的留学生活正式开始了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The image of me arriving the airport" src="/images/macdonald/airport.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;由于学校的宿舍9月10号才能入住，我又事先准备在那之前到爱丁堡熟悉下环境，所以出国前预订了酒店。我一个人拖着一个大箱子和一个小箱子，再背着个书包上了出租车。毕竟是人生地不熟的地方，而且大晚上的，我想坐出租车总不会迷路。途中，司机热情地给我介绍沿途的风景，譬如这个是城堡啦，这个是王子街，是购物的地方啦。对话愉快地结束了的时候，我也抵达了酒店。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;天色已晚，再加上长途飞行让我感到十分疲倦，我期待着赶快入住。就在这时，前台的工作人员跟我说没有找到我的预订信息！我心想，不可能啊！于是我掏出手机把预订确认单给他看，他瞥了一眼又查了查，甚至把电脑屏幕转给我看。结果发现当晚的房间预订里真的没有我的名字！在他把预订确认单拿去仔细看一遍之后，我们才发现是怎么一回事。原来是因为我从杭州当地时间2016年9月8号晚上九点半上的飞机，我订了9月8号的酒店。没问题对不对？可是我忘记考虑一个关键因素——时差了！航班抵达的时候还是英国9月8号，只不过是当地时间的9月8号。而我订的房间却是9月9号的，所以在9月8号的订单里当然找不到我...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The image of hotel staff telling me my name was not on the booking list" src="/images/macdonald/hotel.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;一个人第一次来英国，大晚上的遇上这个事情，让我一时不知道如何是好。脑子里冒出的第一个想法是问问看他们有没有空房间，前台说没有。我于是又问我是不是可以今晚在他们大厅等着，然后第二天入住？他们说不行。大概是因为如果其他客人看到有个陌生女孩睡在大厅会让他们觉得膈应吧。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;再后来可能是因为人生地不熟，也可能因为我太累了，再加上没什么经验，所以没有多想，就直接叫了辆出租车让司机带我去附近的酒店，一个酒店一个酒店的问房位。当时觉得自己运气怎么这么不好，怎么每去一家酒店都客满，爱丁堡的旅游季人可真多呀，司机师傅人真好，每次都自己帮我去问前台。现在回想起来，当时去的酒店都很豪华的样子，而且每个酒店之间司机都开了起码十分钟的车程，我应该是被宰了吧。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;看着计价器里的数字从原本的个位数涨到40十多磅，手机屏幕上的时间已经显示十二点的时候，我心想不能再这样了，于是决定先去24小时麦当劳待着。然后在手机上又看了眼订错了日期的那个预订单，发现他们其实是一家青旅（我之前在中国没有听说过青旅，所以就默认自己订的是酒店了）。和陌生人住一个房间，我不放心，于是便取消了预订，并订了明天入住另一家酒店。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The image of me staying at McDonald's" src="/images/macdonald/mcdonald.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;就这样我开始了在麦当劳逗留的15个小时。想睡却因为怕箱子被顺走而强忍困意。好在不是流露街头，而且还有东西吃，当时的我这样安慰自己。凌晨三四点的时候在麦当劳里遇见了四个中国人，他们也出于某种原因没能住进酒店，当时突然觉得自己有同伴了，好像没那么孤单了，心里感到一阵安慰。第二天我顺利住进了酒店，再之后便住进了学生宿舍。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;当时因为家人没有来得及办签证，再加上我对自己独立的认知，所以毅然决然孤身一人来到从未来过的英国。留学生涯开篇就遇到了这样的事情，现在想想感觉挺滑稽的。当时的自己果然是没有经验，不过好在我当时的心态好。我告诉自己，坏运气都用掉了，剩下的就都是好运气啦。这便是我初到爱丁堡的情形，我想我大概此生都不会忘记吧。&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="first"></category><category term="stories"></category></entry></feed>