<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Wanjing Chen - Life</title><link href="https://cwjwanjing.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://cwjwanjing.github.io/feeds/life.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://cwjwanjing.github.io/</id><updated>2022-02-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>How I travel from the UK to China during pandemic</title><link href="https://cwjwanjing.github.io/blog/enterChinaduringCOVID" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-02-16T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-02-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Wanjing Chen</name></author><id>tag:cwjwanjing.github.io,2022-02-16:/blog/enterChinaduringCOVID</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/UKtoChina/HEL-PVGplane.JPG" alt="" class="headerimg"/&gt;Entering China during pandemic is really hard. I will be sharing with you how I travel from the UK to China during pandemic as a Chinese.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Trip Preparation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until 2021.12, China only allows limited airlines and a limited number of flights per week. Finnair Airline was one of the permitted airlines, so I booked my flight from them. Each week there's only one day that has flights. I booked the flight with the shortest duration, 29 h 35 min, including an overnight transfer for 17 h 50 min. So from London Heathrow (LHR) to Helsinki Vantaa (HEL) was about 2 h 50 min and from Helsinki Vantaa (HEL) to Shanghai Pudong International (PVG) was about 8 h 55 min.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="image"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/UKtoChina/flightexample.png"
  style="display: block;
  margin-left: auto;
  margin-right: auto;
  width: 100%;" alt=""&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The flight I chose&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;All the bookings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's pretty complicated and unpleasant to travel to China during this particular time. Firstly, the flights are very &lt;strong&gt;expensive&lt;/strong&gt;. Mine cost &lt;strong&gt;£3,000&lt;/strong&gt; ish. Then before 7 days of my flight, I needed to take a Coronavirus (COVID-19) test (The nose and tonsils test) and the result required to be negative. I took the NHS Coronavirus (COVID-19) home test because it's free. I was worried about getting a positive result back then because I went to a concert not long before the test date. It was a small one, but the venue was packed. Two days before the flight, I needed a PCR + IgM antibody test (The nose and tonsils + the blood test). I did it at a Chinese pharmacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="image"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/UKtoChina/Igm+pcr.png" style="display: block;
  margin-left: auto;
  margin-right: auto;
  width:100%;" alt=""&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;PCR swab and antibody test result certificate&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are detailed posts on a Chinese app called &lt;em&gt;Red Book&lt;/em&gt; about how to travel from the UK to China. So I followed the posts and knew that I needed to get an additional test: the Nucleocapsid Protein(N Protein) IgM Antibody Test because I took two doses of the Pfizer vaccination. They used something like activated vaccines, which will make the IgM antibody shown as positive. These tests before the flight cost around &lt;strong&gt;£350&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="image"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/UKtoChina/pcr(nProtin).png" style="display: block;
  margin-left: auto;
  margin-right: auto;
  width:100%;" alt=""&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;N Protein IgM antibody test result certificate&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also needed to book the PCR + IgM antibody test at the Helsinki airport during the overnight transfer, which cost &lt;strong&gt;£255&lt;/strong&gt;. The overnight transfer ensures the test results can come out before the next flight from Finland to China. So the total cost before the flight was about &lt;strong&gt;£3605&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Lots of tests&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever since I booked the flight, I've been stressed. Some people got tested positive while at Helsinki airport. I heard some people needed to quarantine in Finland, and some needed to go back to the UK and then quarantine. That means all the money they spent before the flight would be wasted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I needed to book the NHS test in time so that it would come on time. It needs to be the exact 7 days before the flight date. For example, if the flight is on a Wednesday, the test must be done on the previous Wednesday. I did the test twice to make sure there would definitely be a result because I heard some might come out unclear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="image"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/UKtoChina/nhsHomeTesting.jpeg" style="display: block;
  margin-left: auto;
  margin-right: auto;
  width:100%;" alt=""&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;NHS Home Testing Kit, credit: SkyNews - Coronavirus: The inside story of how UK's 'chaotic' testing regime 'broke all the rules'&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ensured the cotton bar got all the liquid it needed by leaving the cotton bar in for longer for both tests. It was not pleasant at all. The result came out fine. On the same day, I needed to start recording my own temperature for the next 7 days. Then it was the PCR + IgM antibody test two days before the flight. They did the nose test for me. It was more pleasant than I did by myself and much deeper. They took my blood samples and I didn't press the wound properly, so it went bruised after a few days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I filled out a few extra forms and had all the negative test results. One day before the flight, I needed to enter a mini app on WeChat to fill out an application form for a green QR code. The information is manually checked, and without the QR code, you can't get the boarding pass. The information includes the vaccination details and proof, passport details, visa status, test results, last 7 days' temperatures, hand-written declaration of staying in the UK for the past 14 days, etc..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Actual Flights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Arriving at Helsinki Vantaa airport&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting onto the first plane was not that different from pre-COVID time. After arriving at Helsinki Vantaa airport, I headed to the transfer service desk. There was a long queue. I showed the staff my green QR code, my passport. Then they pointed me to the PCR + IgM antibody test area. They did the nose + the blood test. The nurse who did the nose went really deep inside. It feels like it reaches my throat from my nose... There was also quite a bit of waiting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="image"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/UKtoChina/HELairport.jpg" style="display: block;
  margin-left: auto;
  margin-right: auto;
  width:100%;" alt=""&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Helsinki Airport&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="image"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/UKtoChina/queueTransferService.jpg" style="display: block;
  margin-left: auto;
  margin-right: auto;
  width:100%;" alt=""&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The queue for the transfer service&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to COVID restrictions, the airport hotel was closed. So any overnight transfer passengers need to stay overnight at the airport. I made a mistake by taking the overnight bag with me to the testing point. It was inconvenient to hold with your arms. I should have picked up the bag after I did the test because the bags were right next to the transfer service desk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="image"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/UKtoChina/overnightbagcollection.jpg" style="display: block;
  margin-left: auto;
  margin-right: auto;
  width:100%;" alt=""&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The overnight bag collection point&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Stay overnight at the airport&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The overnight bag includes a pair of slippers, a travel kit with a toothbrush and toothpaste, some moisturisers, earplugs and an eye mask, as well as the quilt and pillow. A bottle of water. The quilt was a bit thin. It was quite cold at the airport. I didn't sleep well at the airport. I was on my period. My body felt heavy and sore. There were some ambient sounds next to the spot I planned to sleep in. It was loud, and the light was bright. With the help of earplugs and the eye mask, I managed to sleep for 5 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="image"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/UKtoChina/travelkit.jpg" style="display: block;
  margin-left: auto;
  margin-right: auto;
  width:100%;" alt=""&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The travel kit inside the overnight bag&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="image"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/UKtoChina/slippers.jpg" style="display: block;
  margin-left: auto;
  margin-right: auto;
  width:100%;" alt=""&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The slippers that came with the overnight bag&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The flight from Helsinki to Shanghai&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day was pretty easy. I waited for the result to come out and then used the new and old information to apply for the new green QR code. The previous one expired after arriving at the Helsinki airport. The airport staff gave the entire passengers on the same flight as me 2 x €17 vouchers. They can only be used for specific restaurants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The flight journey was mostly the same before COVID. Except, you know for big planes they have 3 columns of seats (As labeled 1,2,3 on the picture below). For the side columns (Column 1 &amp;amp; 3), I think they manually make the middle seat empty. It was good for me. I don’t usually like the window seats. It’s not convenient for me to go to the toilet and it feels like less legroom than the corridor seat. In this case, it was good for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="image"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/UKtoChina/planeColumns.jpg" style="display: block;
  margin-left: auto;
  margin-right: auto;
  width:70%;" alt=""&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Seats on plane&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;After Arriving at Shanghai Pudong Airport&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;While in the airport&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The procedure was quite simple too. I did the COVID (nose and tonsils test) and passed the border control. After collecting my luggage, the staff asked my final destination closer to the exit. My final destination was Hangzhou, which is in Zhejiang province and close to Shanghai. Different provinces have different quarantine policies. (Shanghai is a municipality directly under the Central Government.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="image"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/UKtoChina/arrivePVG.jpeg" style="display: block;
  margin-left: auto;
  margin-right: auto;
  width:100%;" alt=""&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Just landed in Shanghai and stepped outside of the plane&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All quarantine needs to be done in hotels with people monitoring. There are two ways of quarantine for my destination. One is staying at Shanghai hotel for 14 + 7 days. Or 3 + 11 + 7,i.e. 3 days in Shanghai, 11 days in Jiaxing (a city in Zhejiang province, which is between Shanghai and Hangzhou), then 7 days in Hangzhou. I chose the latter one, mainly because I don't need to quarantine for too long consecutively, I could step outside for a little bit when the staff transfer me to a new hotel. Plus the hotel fee would be cheaper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="image"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/UKtoChina/collectluggage.jpeg" style="display: block;
  margin-left: auto;
  margin-right: auto;
  width:100%;" alt=""&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Claiming my luggage at Shanghai Pudong Airport&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, after quarantine in Shanghai, I need to take a train to Hangzhou, and if there’s a positive case in the same train, I will have to be back to quarantine again. It happened to one of my friends. That is not what I want. After I made my choice, I filled in an online form and waited for the staff to take a group of people, including me, to the hotel by a private sanitised bus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The quarantine hotels&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hotels are all randomly assigned to people and you need to pay by yourself. The one in Shanghai that was assigned to me wasn't that great. The hotel is quite old, and I needed to wipe the furniture inside myself. They were dusty. I wasn't sure why it was like that. They did allow essential goods delivery and food that does not need extra care to be stored at normal temperature. It was a twin-bed room. Once I stepped inside the room, I cannot step outside of the room until quarantine ended. There was a small desk outside the door for placing food and parcel deliveries, I could open the door to collect food which the staff delivers. I can open the windows too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="image"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/UKtoChina/ShanghaiHotel.jpg" style="display: block;
  margin-left: auto;
  margin-right: auto;
  width:100%;" alt=""&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A glance of the hotel I got assigned in Shanghai&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fourth morning, I got transferred to a Jiaxing hotel by a private bus. This hotel is where I'm currently staying. I got lucky this time. Although it does not allow food delivery and only allows essential goods delivery, it has a wide range of optional food selections. There are snacks and optional hot food that you can order from the hotel .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, the room was much better than the previous hotel room. The decoration was more modern and felt cosier. Plus, the price was much cheaper than the Shanghai one, almost half cheaper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="image"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/UKtoChina/hotelroom.jpeg" style="display: block;
  margin-left: auto;
  margin-right: auto;
  width:100%;" alt=""&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A photo of the hotel I got assigned in Jiaxing&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="image"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/UKtoChina/hotelroom2.jpeg" style="display: block;
  margin-left: auto;
  margin-right: auto;
  width:100%;" alt=""&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Another photo of the hotel I got assigned in Jiaxing&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later about 9 days in my quarantine, I started to struggle a bit. Good thing that I was working remotely so a big part of the day can be occupied. For the rest of the time I was writing this blog, watching shows, and practicing the Chinese flute Xiao. There were a lot of food in each meal. I didn't really exercise much in the room, so ended up gaining some weight at the end of quarantine. Here are a few photos of the food they provided:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="image"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/UKtoChina/hotelmeal.jpeg" style="display: block;
  margin-left: auto;
  margin-right: auto;
  width:100%;" alt=""&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Quarantine meal&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="image"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/UKtoChina/hotelmeal2.jpeg" style="display: block;
  margin-left: auto;
  margin-right: auto;
  width:100%;" alt=""&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Quarantine meal 2&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the 14th day of my quarantine, I got transferred from Jiaxing to Hangzhou and started the final 7 days of my quarantine. The hotel I stayed in was a relatively old hotel, but I was on a very high floor so the view was better than the previous hotels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="image"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/UKtoChina/view.jpeg" style="display: block;
  margin-left: auto;
  margin-right: auto;
  width:100%;" alt=""&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The view outside the last hotel&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A short summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my experience travelling from the UK to China during the pandemic. My quarantine days are considered to be short. Some provinces require people to quarantine for 28 days. It's hard for Chinese people to enter China, not to mention foreigners. As a person who works in the UK and whose families are in China, I really hope China can reduce the quarantine time or come up with a better way to control the COVID situation soon.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="stories"></category></entry><entry><title>An international student in Edinburgh - Part 2</title><link href="https://cwjwanjing.github.io/blog/Riego-street" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-06-16T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-06-16T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Wanjing Chen</name></author><id>tag:cwjwanjing.github.io,2020-06-16:/blog/Riego-street</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/riego/riegostreet.jpg" alt="" class="headerimg"/&gt; I didn’t get my first choice of accommodation at the University of Edinburgh, I ended up in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Riego Street&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, but I had a good experience.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I studied A levels, a British qualification, in order to study abroad. After my A levels, I decided to go to the University of Edinburgh. This is a story about how I got my accommodation in Year 1, and how it turned out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My A level exam board was CIE, so my grades only came out in August. This, along with some personal issues, meant that I applied for university accommodation quite late.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Renting accommodation privately was not an option since I was not in the UK and could not view flats in person. That meant that university accommodation was my safest bet. Each person was allowed to have five accommodation choices. All of my choices were ensuite because it's a little inconvenient to share one bathroom with four or more people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, when the accommodation assignments came out, I didn't get any of my potential choices. I was assigned to a place called &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Riego Street&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; instead. It was not ensuite. I heard that people got assigned here because they applied late for the accommodation. All of the other choices were already taken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In high school, I lived in a room of four, and we shared a bathroom. That's usually the case for universities in China. So it was alright for me to share a bathroom with other people, and the idea of having my own room already pleased me. I couldn't wait to decorate it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Riego Street&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Riego Street complex forms a U shape; my building was in the middle. When I arrived at the accommodation I saw a big yellow sign which had the University of Edinburgh's logo on it, and 'Riego Street' in big letters. My accommodation is here!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/riego/riegostreet.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I stood at the entrance, I saw many volunteers (most of them were students from higher years), and a red door leading to the reception. A volunteer took me through and gave me an information pack. All the information I needed to know about the accommodation was in there. Then I followed the volunteer to my flat door. After handing me the key, he left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/riego/riegobuilding.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was an A4 paper on the door. It was printed with the Scotland flag and the name of each person who lives in this apartment. My roommates were all nice, they invited me to hang out with them a lot. One of them was from Poland, one of them was Scottish, and one of them was from Malaysia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/riego/flatdoorflag.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw a 10-meter-ish hallway when I opened the flat door. The first room on the left side was the kitchen. It was reasonably spacious. There were four hobs, one sink, one fridge, one dining table, several dining chairs, two big sofas and a tea table—also a toaster, a microwave oven, an oven and some cookware left by previous people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, we had a washing machine. Washing machines were usually shared by the entire building in other accommodation and cost money. A wash cycle (no drying) would normally be around £3. I only need to share with four people, and we didn't need to pay to use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only problems were that there were only four hobs and one refrigerator. My roommates and I all cooked very often. Two people cooking at once got crowded, not to mention three or four people. We could not buy too much food. Otherwise, the fridge got filled up too easily. Thankfully, all of us were considerate. We tried to stagger meal times and to buy the amount of food we would eat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(The picture below is the view from the kitchen window. I took it because I thought my roommates' decoration was cute.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/riego/kitchenwindowoutside.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next room on the left-hand side was the biggest bathroom in the flat. It had a toilet, a sink and a shower. There was another bathroom in the flat which had the same facilities but was smaller. One of the best bits about our flat was that although we had five people, we had two bathrooms which both had a shower. Unlike other four-person flats, which normally have one bathroom with a shower and maybe one extra bathroom without a shower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/riego/riegoflatlayout.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two rooms after the bathroom were bedrooms. The end of the hallway was the smaller bathroom mentioned earlier and a storage room. On the right-hand side of the hallway, there were the remaining three rooms. The rooms were labelled 'A B C D E' respectively. I lived in A.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/riego/riegobedroomlayout.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would say my room was spacious. You could see a big cork notice board on the wall, and below that, there was a heater. On the right-hand side of the room, there was an OK-sized desk with a shelf above it. Next to the desk was a sink. I didn't expect a sink in my room, but it was very convenient. Even when I have morning classes, I didn't need to compete with my roommates for the toilets. The only nuisance was that it was placed opposite the bed. Sometimes when I woke up to pee during the night, my reflection in the mirror shocked me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A single bed was in the left corner, and you could see it when you enter the room, facing the wardrobe. There was a bedside table near the bed. The wardrobe was big enough for me. The single bed was a bit small but matched the size of my quilt cover. The window was placed between the bed and the sink. Sometimes I would use it to people-watch after class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things that surprised me about accommodation in the UK, was their sound insulation. At first, I thought it was only Riego Street which did not have good sound insulation. But I later found out that almost all accommodation (apart from some new builds) had the same problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you speak in the hallway, you need to be prepared for your conversations to be heard by other people. The door seemed to be mostly decorative. However, the sound insulation between each room was alright.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="image"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/riego/riegosurroundingsmap.png" alt=""&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;This graph was made using Google My map&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The location of Riego Street was perfect. The nearest supermarket was 2 minutes walk away. And there was a good range of supermarkets; Tesco Express, Co-op Food, Sainsbury's Local. I went to Sainsbury's Local and Co-op Food most often, because Sainsbury's Local is on my way to school; Co-op Food was the nearest supermarket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A very special thing for me was that there was a Chinese supermarket very close, “Oriental Supermarket”. It was really convenient since I cook Chinese dishes a lot. If I was cooking and forgot an ingredient, it only took me 3 minutes to get it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except for supermarkets, when I wanted to buy toiletries, there was also a Boots and a Superdrug nearby. Even the bank was very close. My bank is RBS, and there was an RBS next door. I like drawing, and there was an art shop in the neighbourhood. Sometimes when I was free, I would go around the shop. Just looking at those painting tools would make me feel happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I wanted to see a movie, I had two choices of cinemas. One was ODEON, and the other was Filmhouse. They were both within 5 minutes walking distance. I was surprised for my first time in Filmhouse because they don't reserve seats, it was first come first serve. I thought all European cinemas were like this until I went to ODEON. Filmhouse was unusual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I wanted to go to a concert, the Usher Hall was a good choice. There was a performance almost every night. It was a pity that I didn't find out about it until my second year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main shopping street, Princes Street was just over 10 minutes walk. It took a similar time to get to Edinburgh Castle. I often took a walk with friends there after dinner. Since the castle is on the hill, when you look down at the city during sunset, you can feel the beauty of the city even more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Occasionally, when I didn't want to cook, there were also many restaurants for me to choose. There are Japanese cuisine, Chinese cuisine, China Red (Chinese buffet), grilled fish store, Korean cuisine, Nando's (fried chicken) and lots more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I study computer science, so my classes were all on the main campus. It took me 15 minutes walk to the campus. So I didn't need to worry about being late for lectures even if I woke up late.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a shame that I didn't take many photos of the accommodation. I can only recall the pictures in my mind. Overall, I think Riego Street was good accommodation, it was definitely good value for money. All bills were included in the price of 125 pounds a week. Even though I didn't get my first choice of accommodation, I was pleased being assigned there.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="stories"></category></entry><entry><title>An international student in Edinburgh - Part 1</title><link href="https://cwjwanjing.github.io/blog/Edinburgh" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-06-04T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-06-04T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Wanjing Chen</name></author><id>tag:cwjwanjing.github.io,2020-06-04:/blog/Edinburgh</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/macdonald/airport.jpg" alt="" class="headerimg"/&gt; This is the story of my first evening in Edinburgh. Something unexpected happened...&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Preface&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the midst of a global pandemic, and without realising it, 2020 has entered June. Initially, my graduation ceremony would have been held in 20 days. However, due to the coronavirus, it’s still up in the air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started to think back on my degree and even what I might have done differently given the chance. I’ve learned many things and experienced many things. Here I want to share some of the most memorable examples. This is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;An international student in Edinburgh - Part 1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;One night in McDonald's&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the 8th of September, 2016, I flew to the UK. It was 9ish in the evening when I arrived at Edinburgh airport. Just after I stepped outside the plane, I felt a chill in the air. Edinburgh evenings in September are cold. The moment when the customs officer stamped my passport, I knew my life of studying abroad had begun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The image of me arriving the airport" src="/images/macdonald/airport.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since my university accommodation was available for checking in only from the 10th of September, and I was planning to familiarise myself with Edinburgh's environment earlier than that, I booked a hotel before my departure. Carrying my luggage; a big suitcase, a small suitcase and a backpack, I got in the taxi. I figured taking a taxi would be the safest choice for me, given that I knew nothing about Edinburgh’s buses and it was already dark. I didn't want to get lost. During the ride, the driver was friendly, introducing the tourist spots as we passed by them, such as this is the castle, this is Prince’s Street (the place for shopping) etc. When we reached the end of our conversation, I arrived at the hotel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was late and I was exhausted from my flight, so I was hoping to check in quickly. However, just as I was imagining a soft, warm bed, the reception staff told me that he couldn’t find my booking! How could this be possible?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took out my phone and showed him my booking confirmation letter, he had a glance at it and then rechecked the list, even turning the computer screen for me to see. Surprisingly, the booking lists on that night genuinely didn't have my name on it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After he read the confirmation letter thoroughly, we realised what the problem was. It's because I took the flight at 9:30 PM Chinese time on the 8th of September. My hotel booking was for the 9th of September. However, I’d forgotten to take into account time going backwards as I flew west, and so I had landed in Edinburgh still on the 8th of September! No wonder my name was not on the booking list…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The image of hotel staff telling me my name was not on the booking list" src="/images/macdonald/hotel.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first time in the UK (alone!) and this unexpected thing happened; I was stunned into silence for a while. The first thing came to my mind was asking them if they have any rooms available tonight. They said no. Then I thought maybe I could ask them if I could stay in the lobby for tonight and check in tomorrow? Again they said no, probably because other customers might find a strange girl sleeping in the lobby off-putting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later on, it might be due to my tiredness or my unfamiliarity with the surroundings, not to mention I wasn’t very experienced, I called a taxi without thinking further. I asked the driver to take me to the nearby hotels and ask each one whether they have rooms available tonight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One by one the hotels said no. I was wondering why I was so unlucky, why every hotel we visited did not have a room available? But I thought, Edinburgh is surely busy in the tourist season, and the driver is so kind, asking the hotels for me every time. When I look back on it right now, the hotels we visited looked all very fancy, and the travelling times between each hotel were at least 10 minutes, I guess he was just racking up a nice fare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the number in the taximeter was increasing past 40 pounds and the time displayed on the phone was already twelve o'clock, I thought that I couldn't keep doing this any longer. I decided to stay at a 24-hour McDonald's. On the way there, I rechecked the booking confirmation letter, surprisingly, I realised it was actually a youth hostel. (There are very few youth hostels in China, so I assumed it was a hotel.) I wasn’t comfortable with the idea of living with strangers in a room, so I cancelled the booking, and booked another hotel for the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The image of me staying at McDonald's" src="/images/macdonald/mcdonald.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From then, my 15-hour stay at McDonald's started. I felt really sleepy, but I forced myself to stay awake in case my luggage was stolen. I tried to comfort myself by thinking "thankfully I'm not staying on the street, and I still have food".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the early morning, around three or four o'clock, I met four Chinese people in the McDonald's. They had hotel problems too and were in the same boat as me. I felt less lonely and a little comforted. The next day I successfully checked in, and afterwards successfully moved in my student accommodation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My parents back then were not able to get their visas in time, and I considered myself independent enough, so I decided to come to Edinburgh alone for my first time in the UK. Experiencing this kind of thing at the beginning of my study abroad seems funny to me when I think about it now. I was quite inexperienced, but I had a positive attitude at least. I encouraged myself that I've used up all the bad luck, and the rest will all be good luck. That was my first impression of Edinburgh, which I think I'll never forget.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="first"></category><category term="stories"></category></entry></feed>